Takyoung Kim

Incoming Ph.D. Student at the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign (UIUC)

 ♦ youngerous.github.io
 ■ tk30@illinois.edu
 in in/youngerous
 ♦ Google Scholar

Interests

My research interest lies in the intersection of Natural Language Processing and Communication. I am particularly interested in building communicative language models (LMs) that can understand social and cognitive context, evaluating preference during interactions, and exploring how LMs compose knowledge both from parametric and external sources.

Education

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, IL, USA Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science Advisor: Dilek Hakkani-Tür Korea University, Seoul, South Korea Master of Engineering, Industrial Management Engineering Advisor: Pilsung Kang (now at Seoul National University) Thesis: Relaxing Unrealistic Assumptions of Dataset and Evaluation Metric in Dialogue State Tracking Sungkyunkwan University, Seoul, South Korea Mar 2013 - Aug 2020 Bachelor of Science in Engineering, Interdisciplinary Program of Convergent Software

Publications *=Equal Contribution

Bachelor of Media & Communication (Leave of absence for military service: Feb 2015 - Nov 2016)

- [1] DSTEA: Improving Dialogue State Tracking via Entity Adaptive Pre-training \(\begin{align*}\)
 Yukyung Lee, \(\frac{Takyoung Kim}{}\), Hoonsang Yoon, Pilsung Kang, Junseong Bang, Misuk Kim
 Knowledge-Based Systems (Q1, Impact Factor: 8.8)

 Workshop on Knowledge Augmented Methods for NLP

 KnowledgeNLP, KDD 2023
- [2] KoSBi: A Dataset for Mitigating Social Bias Risks Towards Safer Large Language Model Applications (*)>
 Hwaran Lee*, Seokhee Hong*, Joonsuk Park, <u>Takyoung Kim</u>, Gunhee Kim, Jung-Woo Ha
 Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Industry Track)

 ACL 2023
- SQuARe: A Large-Scale Dataset of Sensitive Questions and Acceptable Responses Created Through Human-Machine Collaboration (**)

 Hwaran Lee*, Seokhee Hong*, Joonsuk Park, <u>Takyoung Kim</u>, Meeyoung Cha, Yejin Choi, Byoungpil Kim, Gunhee Kim, Eun-Ju Lee, Yong Lim, Alice Oh, Sangchul Park, Jung-Woo Ha

 Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Oral, Best Paper Nomination)

 ACL 2023
- [4] Development of a Framework for Road Test Score Prediction and Significant Keywords Extraction based on Vehicle Specification Data

YongGi Jeong, Kyoosung So, <u>Takyoung Kim</u>, Jina Kim, Seungwan Seo, Seonggye Lee, Sunwoo Kim, Pilsung Kang *Journal of Korean Institute of Industrial Engineers*

- [5] Oh My Mistake!: Toward Realistic Dialgoue State Tracking including Turnback Utterances

 Takyoung Kim, Yukyung Lee, Hoonsang Yoon, Pilsung Kang, Junseong Bang, Misuk Kim

 Towards Semi-Supervised and Reinforced Task-Oriented Dialog Systems

 SereTOD, EMNLP 2022
- [6] Mismatch between Multi-turn Dialogue and its Evaluation Metric in Dialogue State Tracking Takyoung Kim, Hoonsang Yoon, Yukyung Lee, Pilsung Kang, Misuk Kim

 Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short)

 ACL 2022
- [7] Building an Integrated Framework of Korean Text Summarization and Text-to-Speech (**)

 Takyoung Kim, Jina Kim, Hyeongwon Kang, Subin Kim, Pilsung Kang

 Journal of Korean Institute of Industrial Engineers

 JKIIE 2022

Preprint & Under Review

[8] Learning to Explore and Select for Coverage-Conditioned Retrieval-Augmented Generation Takyoung Kim, Kyungjae Lee, Young Rok Jang, Ji Yong Cho, Gangwoo Kim, Minseok Cho, Moontae Lee Preprint [9] Revealing User Familiarity Bias in Task-Oriented Dialogue via Interactive Evaluation Takyoung Kim, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Sanghwan Bae, Sungdong Kim

Preprint

Research Experience

Korea University | Data Science & Business Analytics Lab, Seoul, South Korea 🗹

Apr 2024 - Present

Research Associate (Advisor: Pilsung Kang)

Working on retrieval-augmented language models specialized in Korean news domain

LG AI Research | Advanced Machine Learning Lab, Seoul, South Korea 🗗

Apr 2023 - Mar 2024

Research Intern (Mentors: Kyungjae Lee, Moontae Lee)

Worked on enhancing long-form response quality of large language models via planning and alignment [8]

NAVER AI Lab | Language Research Team, Seongnam, South Korea 🗹

Jul 2022 - Jan 2023

Research Intern (Mentor: Sungdong Kim)

Worked on revealing innate bias in task-oriented dialogue research via interactive study [9] Worked on constructing safety benchmark for sensitive questions [3] and social biases [2]

Korea University | Data Science & Business Analytics Lab, Seoul, South Korea

Sep 2020 - Jun 2022

Research Assistant (Advisor: Pilsung Kang)

Worked on analyzing realistic biases and limitations of dialogue state tracking [6, 5, 1]

Developed algorithms and pipelines in various domains, such as news [7], car [4] and ocean waves

Korea University | Data Science & Business Analytics Lab, Seoul, South Korea

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

Undergraduate Research Intern (Advisor: Pilsung Kang)

Designed spatial/temporal architecture reflecting optical flow for video deepfake detection

Presentations and Talks

Selective Masking for Task-Adaptive Pre-Training

Korean Institute of Industrial Engineers Conference (Spring)

Jun 2021

A Life of Turning into Software

Software Edu Fest, Naver Connect Foundation

Jul 2020

Oct 2019

Honors and Awards

Research Ideation Contest | Best Student Feedback Award | Korea University

MyData Acting Hackathon | The Grand Prize (2nd Place, 2,500\$) | Ministry of Science and ICT

Feb 2021, Dec 2021

Merit-based Scholarship | Computer Science Coursework | Sungkyunkwan University

Spring 2018, Fall 2018

Teaching Experience

T02459101 - Natural Language Processing Hankuk University of Foreign Studies

Feb 2024 - Present

Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Yukyung Lee)

Industrial Machine Learning LG Electronics Head Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

Research Mentoring Hyundai Mobis

Research Project Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

Industrial Machine Learning and Deep Learning LG Innotek, SK Hynix

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)

Academic Service

Conference Reviewer NeurIPS Datasets & Benchmarks (2022-24), EMNLP (2023), EMNLP Industry Track (2023), EACL (2024)

Journal Reviewer Knowledge-Based Systems (2023-24)

Others ACL Rolling Review (2023-24)